Good Morning!
You may be seated. Thank you.
Hallelujah!
Let me just give you a message from the heart.
When you look at the whole thing,
Christianity has become just a surface - human wisdom.
Christianity seems to be human wisdom.
There is no difference any longer between Christianity and religion.
So even when you listen to the news or whatever comment,
they classify them as religion.
Christianity is not a religion.
Jesus came to restore the relationship and fellowship between God and man.
He came to restore this relationship.
Christianity lies in the heart.
It is all about the Word of God in our heart.
Tell your neighbour.
[It is all about the Word of God in our heart.]
I can't hear you.
Today, Christianity has turned to the Word of God in our mouth.
People believe that they should just confess, "I am a Christian". Simple.
Your neighbourhood knows you are coming to the church
and consequently that you are a Christian, a believer - are you such in heart?
That is the question you need to ask.
Because you carry a Bible, a Cross, bear Joshua, Timothy, Deborah - are you such in heart?
If you are such in heart, that is the work of faith the Bible is talking about.
"Amen!" Are you such in heart?
"In the name of Jesus!"
Are you such in heart?
"Thank You, Jesus!"
That is what Christianity is all about.
That is what Jesus is interested in.
That is what pleases Jesus.
You are in the church.
Are you such in heart?
Are you telling me your spirit is inside the church?
Let us quickly look at the Book of Colossians Chapter 3:
"Living as those made alive in Christ.
Since, then, you have been raised with Christ, set your hearts on things above, where Christ is,
seated at the right hand of God.
Set your minds on things above, not on earthly things."
Let me take you to verse 23.
"Whatever you do, work at it with all your heart,
as working for the Lord, not for human masters,
since you know that you will receive an inheritance from the Lord as a reward..."
Take your time to read that Colossians' Book,
1 Chronicles 28:9,
James 4:3,
and Luke 16:15 when you get home.
Here you are in the church.
Are you such in heart?
Because Christianity lies in the heart.
Jesus looks at our motive behind our action but men look at the action.
You are sitting down, you are laughing - that is all what man can see
but Jesus looks at the motive behind your sitting.
I mean, Jesus looks at why you do what you do but men look at what you do.
T.B. Joshua.
But the motive behind it...
That is what Christianity is all about.
You believe God that it will rain - you go ahead and plant crops.
I believe it will rain and I go ahead and plant crops without waiting for the rain.
People see you as a Christian because you are called Joshua, Timothy, Deborah, Esther,
you go to church as a pastor, Christian, bishop, prophet
and you have sound knowledge of the Scripture;
but don't forget: A man may be a Christian but not such in heart.
A man may have sound knowledge of the Bible and not such in heart.
In 1 Chronicles 28:9, the Lord searches all hearts and understands all the intents of the thoughts.
If you are not such in heart, how do you speak to God; how will God speak to you?
Because the Bible says, the Word of God in our heart is our contact with God.
Let someone say, "The Word of God in our heart is our contact with God".
It is His contact with us too.
"You want to speak to me?" -
the Word of God in my heart will contact.
I want to speak to Him - the Word of God in my heart.
How do you speak to God when you are not such in heart?
You have been dancing since morning. Are you such in heart?
Whatever your heart engages on influences your conduct and your character.
If your heart does not contact the Word of God, nothing can be achieved in God.
You can be seen as a Christian because you are often seen with a big Bible and big Cross
but God does not see you as such because of the motive behind your being a Christian.
The new year is about...
You cannot continue this way.
If you continue this way without God's Word in your heart -
people see you as a Christian whereas you cannot contact God
and God cannot contact you - what kind of Christian is this?
You cannot contact God and God cannot contact you.
The only means, the only grace to contact you is that Word in your heart
but where is that Word in your heart?
The next year is not going to be this year in attitude, character, challenges, trial, condition.
Tell your neighbour, "Man has to power to testify, witness about Christ".
A man can say, "Jesus is Lord! Jesus is the Redeemer!
Jesus is the Healer! Whosoever believes in Him shall not perish but have everlasting life".
Man has that power but the Holy Spirit testifies, witnesses.
Knowing facts about Jesus does not change our relationship with Him.
So, read your Bible with devotion.
Discover what God has to say to you each day.
Tell your neighbour, "Knowing facts about Jesus does not change our relationship with Him".
Again.
[Knowing facts about Jesus does not change our relationship with Him.]
So, read your Bible with devotion.
When you see someone who is doing good, very nice, don't be in a haste to see him as good
because you don't know his motive.
This is what they have been using to deceive you - you politicians - all over the world.
"Okay, I will do this, I will do that."
They give you food, they give you everything, they campaign...
But when they get to the position, they change.
"I will do this!" - you follow them, "Hey!"
You will build a school; you will do this; you will improve the school, the economy.
All over the world you see, "Hey!"
Food, bring money out to the city, share money, give everyone - and you follow.
By the time they get there, the story changes.
When you see someone who is doing good and is loving,
don't be in a haste because you don't know his motive.
When you see someone who is preaching the Gospel of our Lord Jesus Christ,
claiming to witness for Christ, let us take our time before calling him a pastor or Christian
because you don't know his motive.
Jesus' focus is the motive behind what we do - what you do and why you do it.
That is His focus.
His focus is the motive behind what we do and why we do it,
what you say and why you say it.
That is His focus.
Many of us have been deceived when it comes to relationships
because a man is very nice, a woman is nice, caring and loving -
"Oh, you have forgotten; this is a nice person."
But as time goes on, the story changes.
Man has the power to decide.
You can decide to just walk out of this place.
The Spirit of God will not grab you and say, "No, don't go!"
You can decide as we are talking, "No, no, what this man is saying, I can't stand it" and walk out
and the Spirit of God, Jesus, will not say, "No, come back"; He will leave you to go.
That is discretion given to everyone.
That is why Jesus asked the man at the pool of Bethesda,
"What will I do for you? What do you want me to do?"
He said, "No, I have been here for many years; no one to carry me to the pool".
"What do you want me to do now?"
If the man said, "No, no, don't talk to me; go your way!", Jesus would leave him.
That is discretion.
The man said, "Please, help me".
Man has the power to decide.
You can decide to pray which many of us have been doing,
just when you have a problem - "Jesus!"
You can decide to pray early morning; it is a normal routine.
You wake up early in the morning - "Oh, children, let us pray."
"In the name of Jesus" - you are the one praying; Jesus does not know.
Exercising the will through the mind but the Holy Spirit has the power of choice.
Jesus tests our heart to reward us.
Tell your neighbour.
[Jesus tests our heart to reward us.]
I can't hear you.
All this running helter skelter, "I'm a pastor, I'm a Christian, I'm this",
carrying this, all this appearance, all this shouting, "Hey!",
praying, fasting, "Hey, my God!", going to the mountain -
they say, "He is a prayer warrior; he is this, that".
Jesus tests our heart to reward us.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The question remains - are you such in heart?
What is your motive?
Jesus tests our heart to give us according to our efforts.
Tell your neighbour.
I can't hear you.
[Jesus tests our heart to give us according to our efforts.]
What is the state of your heart?
Your heart must be at its best because the Holy Spirit, the Spirit of the Father
expresses Himself through your heart.
The Spirit of God expresses Himself through your heart.
All this, "In the name of Jesus!" - are you such in heart?
"Amen!!"
Are you such in heart?
"Let us pray!"
This is why it is always difficult to go through trials.
No one can go through trials without the Word in the heart.
No one can say, "Jesus is Lord!", without the Word in the heart.
Tell your neighbour.
[No one can say, "Jesus is Lord!", without the Word in the heart.]
So, where are we going?
And I'm very very sure - that is why I'm saying this -
a lot of percentage in our midst here are not such in heart.
That is why I'm bitter.
For you to go to the New Year - with the trials, tribulations, situations I am seeing that are coming -
you need the Word of God in your heart to contact Jesus.
Tell your neighbour, "I need the Word in my heart to contact Jesus".
It is the Word Jesus also uses to contact you - the Word in your heart.
What I'm looking at, I'm looking round -
if you are my neighbour, I will know;
if you share the same inheritance, I will know;
if you are my family, I will know.
I can see.
This is just celebration - percentage of us here.
For how long shall we continue this - trials, persecution, tribulation?
No one can say, "Jesus is Lord!" genuinely without the Word in the heart.
Genuinely.
Anybody can say, "Jesus is Lord!" - you don't need license for that - but genuinely...
So, rise up and let us pray.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I say to your heart, "Awake, in the name of Jesus!"
The Holy Spirit is at the door of your heart.
Say, "My heart, awake!"
The Holy Spirit is at the door of my heart - awake!
Yes.
The Holy Spirit is there knocking, saying, "Awake!"
That is, open the door.
The Holy Spirit is at the door of your heart right now!
I say to your heart, "Awake!"
In Jesus' name!
Committing the Word of God to memory is valuable but does not bring Jesus to the scene.
Tell your neighbour.
Learning the history of the Book of the Bible is valuable.
You can be a lecturer, you can teach, you can get your daily bread,
getting money - it is valuable but does not bring Jesus to the scene.
Say, "In the name of Jesus!" - where is Jesus because the Word is not from your heart.
My heart, hear the voice of God.
My heart hear the voice of God
My heart hear the voice of Holy Spirit
Let there be freedom
Let there be rest
In my heart in my mind
And in my soul in Jesus' name
Let there be freedom
Let there be rest in my heart
Did you listen to that?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When you pray, you do not receive; when you ask, you do not receive
because you pray and ask with wrong motives.
That is why you don't receive.
I'm not surprised.
Many of you just let...
It is a normal life - we have to pray in the morning, in the afternoon, in the evening.
You just pray, not that...
You pray, you do not receive; you ask, you do not receive
because you ask with wrong motives.
'Wrong motive' could be - there is no Word in your heart
and the Word in our heart makes us Christians.
The Word of God in our heart makes us Christians.
The Word of God in our heart is our contact with Jesus.
It is His contact with us.
So, now you need this Word.
Now you are about to enter the new year.
By the time you leave here, you know the next thing to do.
It is not to go to the party; you are to work on your spiritual life.
You can see the reason now.
For someone to be saying he is a Christian, whereas Jesus Himself does not know.
It is not in the record that you are a Christian; you are a religious person.
Nothing makes us Christians but the Word in our heart.
The Word in our heart is our contact.
"Hello."
And the Lord will say, "Hi, what do you want?"
The Word in your heart.
That is why you must have freedom, a free heart - a heart without a grudge.
We have damaged our heart.
Nursing a grudge, nursing bad feelings towards others damages our heart.
Tell your neighbour.
Nursing a grudge, pain of the past, bitterness, envy, jealousy, bad feelings towards others,
damages our heart.
The same heart is the contact point.
The Bible says the Spirit of the Father expresses Himself through our heart
and the heart we are talking about is damaged.
You have to begin to repair your heart.
The Spirit of the Father expresses Himself through our heart and the same heart is damaged.
Nursing a pain of the past, grudge, bad feelings towards others.
You say, "No, I will not agree."
Nursing an unforgiving spirit damages the heart.
So, you can see now.
So, you have to work now; you have a lot of work to do
because I do not want you to enter a new year with all this.
And you continue to say, it is witches and wizards;
your partner is the one attacking you.
Nobody attacked you; you are the one that damaged your heart.
There is no landing for God; there is no point for God to talk to you.
There must be a point.
"Hello."
Through what? - Heart.
The Word in the heart is our contact with God.
It is His contact with us but the heart is damaged.
Tell your neighbour, "Forgive them!"
I'm not saying, "Forgive him"; I said, "Forgive them!"
Say, "Forgive them and move forward!"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So, let us pray for our nation, your country, your continent.
Your flag, any contact you have - raise it up!
Ask God to redeem your nation and leaders, in the name of Jesus Christ.
I can't hear you.
[Amen.]
In the name of Jesus Christ.
Prayer For The Nations
With Prophet T.B. Joshua
Open your lips - ask God to redeem your country, nation, leaders,
in Jesus Christ's name we pray.
[Amen.]
I can't hear you.
Right now, commit your journey of righteousness -
ask God to continue to strengthen you.
Because when you leave here, you continue the journey of righteousness.
With the message you have received today - journey of righteousness,
journey of uprigntness, journey of holiness.
Ask God to strengthen you.
Ask God to strengthen you in your journey of righteousness, uprightness, holiness,
faithfulness, obedience, humility and love.
The SCOAN Sunday Mass Prayer
Strengthen me, Lord.
In Jesus Christ's name we pray.
Don't forget, Christianity lies in the heart.
Whatever you do, whatever you say must be such in heart.
I pray the Lord gives you an obedient heart, in Jesus' name!
Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT: Mel Flowers 17/01/2019
RV: Pavel Tatyana Zheleznyakov 09/02/2019